Damon Teer

Summary

Business Information Technology Graduate from Queen's University with a passion for Software Development and IT technologies.

Software Development Experience

My Notes Application Project (JavaScript): I developed a Notes app using only JavaScript and Local Storage. It's a simple application that allows the user to add, edit, delete, and save notes using Local Storage. This project utilised the following features of JavaScript: Local Storage, ES6 Import/Export Syntax, Classes, Arrow Functions, Static Methods, Callback Functions, Event Listeners, QuerySelector, GetElementByld, Template Strings, Class List, CSS Pseudo-Classes, Flexbox and HTML5 Data Attributes.

Web Application Development (Final Year Project): Developed a web application using PHP, JavaScript, and SQL to help provide a solution for primary school teachers who are struggling with basic computing skills. This incorporated a self-created content management system with secure sessions for both admin and standard user.

Data Science with R programming: In my final year of university, I partook in a module called data visualisation and interpretation. This involved the use of R programming to analyse large datasets incorporating ways to visualise this data in a useful way for interpretation. Within the scope of the final project, we took a large dataset, cleaned it and implemented ggplot2 methodologies to present said data in a graphical format. We then proceeded to interpret and identify trends.

Java Object Orientated Programming: During my first year in university, we focused on the fundamentals of programming. Covering the basics from writing pseudo code to the four pillars of objecting orientated programming (Abstraction, Encapsulation, Inheritance and Polymorphism). I also garnered an insight into functional programming concepts such as lambdas and recursion.

Link to some of my projects! → https://github.com/damon059

Education

- Degree: 2.1 BSC Business Information Technology from Queen's University
- A Level ABB Rathmore Grammar School, Belfast 2008-2016

Employment History

Business Development Executive to Team Leader at Randox Laboratories (2020-present)

- Management of a team of 5 sales personnel based in the Vietnam market.
- Responsible for developing a strategy to grow and maintain the Randox business in the Vietnam Market (Grew to over £2,000,000 in 2021)
- Representing Randox at a corporate level while attending international events and conferences
- Collaborating and supporting our international business partners.
- Maintaining a high level of product knowledge to train new partners and staff.

IT Technical Support at St. Francis Primary School (2018-2019)

- Managed/updated a back-end content management system
- Managed/updated the schools front-end web design
- Maintained the school's network
- Provided software and hardware support

Contact Info

Phone Number: +447565883821

Email Address:

damonteer059@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

<u>linkedin.com/in/damon-teer-3849a7150/</u>

Skills List

- JavaScript (React, Angular)
- Java
- PHP
- _R_
- CSS
- HTML
- Version Control (Git)
- Pvthon
- UX/UI Design

References

Gavin Patton (Mentor) – Software Engineer at Puppet

Tel: +44 7933 279135

Marie Rice – Vice Principal at St. Francis Primary School Tel: 028 90972603 mrice296@stfrancis.lurgan .ni.sch.uk

Anna Croke – Clinical Services Operations Manager at Randox Laboratories Tel: 028 94422413

Kevin Campbell – IT Technical Manager at Queen's University MBC Tel: +44 7870 401016